### E: talk@davidcallanan.co.uk www.davidcallanan.co.uk

# NAN GRAPHIC/MOTION DESIGNER

**ABOUT ME** 

When choosing to go to university I possibly made a small mistake in choosing to do a theatre degree, as in the three years I have been at Lancaster, I have, alongside my degree spent all the time available to me becoming a freelance Graphic and Motion Designer.

Although I have not undergone any formal training, I have had the opportunity to hone my own skills in C4D and the adobe suite as well as other software packages over the past three years and as such can now pick up new software incredibly quickly, as well as navigate any issues I face without problem.

In addition to this I have had the opportunity to create work for clients including Liverpool University and the FASS department in Lancaster University on a freelance basis.

In my degree I was able to focus on digital media, design and animation in a Live Art/Theatre setting. As such I posses a wide range of skills including projection mapping, lighting, sound, film and other 'Live' skills. I have also produced several plays and as such have experience with dealing with the press as well as copywriting, project management and time keeping skills.



#### **PERSONAL**

Janurary 1994

Name David Callanan

**Address** 

D.O.B

Phone

Email talk@davidcallanan.co.uk

Website www.davidcallanan.co.uk



#### ONLINE



facebook.com/dcallanan

vimeo.com/davidcallanan



#### **EDUCATION**

BA (Hons) Theatre Studies Minoring in Design (Averaging 1st Class) **Lancaster University** Lancaster, Uk

Three A Grades at A level,

Chester CHS.

10 GCSE all A\* to B Grades. St Joseph's High School, Wrexham.

2013-16

2010-12

2005-10

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### **CURRENT POSITIONS**

Freelance Graphic and Motion 2014-16 Designer - Lancaster.

Casual Technician LX/SFX/AV 2014-16 Lancaster University: LICA.

Events Crew (Technician) 2015-16 LUSU.

#### PREVIOUS POSITIONS

Web Designer: 2012-14 The Gatehouse Veterinary Centre

Service Positions: Rosset Hall 2011-13 Hotel; River Island Fashion.



#### **SKILLS**

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe InDesign

Adobe After Effects

Cinema 4D

Microsoft Office

HTML (5) and CSS (3)

Adobe Premier Pro





#### **REFERENCES**

Prof. Andrew Quick, Academic Reference, Artistic Director ITD, Lancaster University.

Contact Available upon Request

Client Contact Details Avaible upon Request Dani Morgan Dodd -Creating Conversations.

Nic Steele -Liverpool University VPU.

### E: talk@davidcallanan.co.uk www.davidcallanan.co.uk

# DAVID CALLANAN

**GRAPHIC/MOTION DESIGNER** 



#### **PORTFOLIO**

#### 1. Creating Conversations

Creating conversations is a community outreach project attempting to bring the older and younger generations of Lancaster together through art. They required print and digital advertising and branding.

## 2. Liverpool University - Veterinary PostGrad Unit

Re branding of Liverpool University's VPU. The design is centered around the three strands of teaching that they offer. Domestic animals, Farm, and Equine.

#### 3. Ainscough Music

A lancaster based Musician and Music teacher required both print and digital advertisments. The poster, flyer and Motion Graphics designs can be seen in full on my online portfolio. The design process involved modelling and animation in C4D and compositing in photoshop and after effects as well as colour touch up work and copywriting.

#### 4. Motion Showreel

My motion graphics showreel is available on my website www.davidcallanan.co.uk along with my full portfolio of work.

#### 5. The 39 Steps

The 39 Steps by Patrick Barlow, is a farsical theatrical production. Produced by Lancaster University Theatre Group. The four seperate designs re-enforce the variety of charchters the four actors play over the cousre of the production









